#大家好 現在這個小狗哇 (註︰狗狗已經不可以再叫"puppies"了，但他仍叫「小狗」，所以還是譯成"puppies")
Hi everyone! Now the puppies,
#都已經半歲啦
are already half a year old.
#我們把它秤一下
Let's weigh them.
#剛好買了一把新秤子
We've just bought a new weigh
#我們秤一下
Let's weigh.
#看一下它們多重啦
and see how heavy they are.
#先秤你這條啊
This one first.
#你 比較聽話
You, you are a good dog.
#哎喲
Ooiyo!
Aya!
#100
A hundred and (Note: unit is "jin". 1 "jin" = 500 g)
#42
Forty-two
#142
A hundred and forty two
#142秤減去我
A hundred and forty two less my
#105
a hundred and five
#142 105
A hundred and forty two, a hundred and five
#拿計算機一下 算不出來
Where's my calculator? I can't do it.
#142減105
A hundred and forty two minus a hundred and five.
#37斤
Thirty seven "jin".
#哪條 就這條
Which one? This one here?
#這已經長37斤啦
It's already 37 "jin"!
#哇瑟 (這怪叫較難明，所以不直譯了)
Oh, God!
#37斤了你
You're already 37 "jin"!
#半年就長那麼重
You get that heavy in just half a year.
#跟豬一樣的 哦
Just like a pig, oh.
#這裡可能受傷啦 誰叫你要打架
This may be a wound. I've told you not to fight.
#你要秤是不是
You come to try the weigh, don't you?
#小黑
Blacky!
#秤一下小黑
Let's weigh blacky.
#小黑更輕
Blacky weighs even less.
#139
A hundred and thirty nine.
#小黑
Blacky!
#139減去105
Subtract a hundred and five from a hundred of thirty nine.
#139
A hundred and thirty nine
#這樣子
Naughty!
#34 (註︰聽到清哥好像說「三四」似的)
Three four
#啊
Ah?
#34
Three four
#34斤 小黑
Thirty four "jin", Blacky.
#誒 小黑怎樣那麼重
Eh? Why is Blacky that heavy?
#看它那麼小 還那麼重
She looks tiny but she's so heavy.
#還有其它呢
Where is the rest?
#全跑啦
All ran away.
#哈哈 最壯的
Haha, the most bulky one.
#你看這條 最壯的這條
Look at this dog. He's the most bulky one.
#這條是最大個的哦
This is the biggest dog.
#哎喲 這條最少40斤 (註︰原字幕在此之前出現了極短時間的「哈哈」，我想只是手誤)
Oyo! This is at least 40 "jin".
#抱都抱王動了
I can only barely hold it.
#153
A hundred and fifty three
#哎
Ya!
#153
A hundred and fifty three
#153減
A hundred and fifty three minus
#53減5斤
Fifty three minus 5 "jin" is,
#49斤
Forty nine "jin"!
#哇 都比別人胖了十多斤
Wa! He's a heavier than the others by a dozen "jin".
#狗 過來
Dog! Come here!
#抱一下你 嗯 這條那麼輕
Let me hold you. Um! This is so light.
#來
Come on!
#141斤
A hundred and forty one "jin".
#141
A hundred and forty one
#141減去
A hundred and forty one minus
#41減去
forty one minues 5
#這個36斤 (註︰五隻小狗只有兩隻是公的，全身灰黃色嘴巴黑黑的一隻，攝影小哥最喜歡的一隻)
She is 36 "jin".
#這條挺壯的
She's rather bulky.
#走 等下再啃啊
Let's go. Crunch your bone later.
#走 秤一下你
Let's go! Let me weigh you.
#哇 這條
Wa! This is
##這條小公狗
This is a little male dog.
#這個攝影小哥最喜歡的
This is Mr Cameraman's most favourite dog.
#139斤
A hundred and thirty nine "jin".
#39減5
Thirty nine minus five
#34斤
Thirty four "jin".
#那不是跟小黑一樣重
So he weighs the same as Blacky?
#虛胖 被你寵的
Puffy. You spoil him.
#這條狗看上去那麼胖
This dog looks that fat,
#它是虛胖哦 肯定是一身肥膘
but he's just puffy. The fat must be all over his body,
#沒有瘦肉的
without even a bit of lean muscles.
#小黑就有瘦肉
Blacky should have lean muscles.
#你看 這個
Look! This dog
#這個 這個 這個全是肥肉
he is, he is, he is full of fat.
#多鍛煉[SIC]身體知不知道
You need much more training. Do you get it?
#知不知道
Do you?
#鍛煉[SIC]身體 對身體有好處的
More training, it's good for your body.
#跑得也比較快一點啊
You can run faster.
#嗯 給你按一下摩
Um. Give you a massage.
#這些狗都好聽話的哦
They are very good dogs now.
#天天待在這 不走的
They simply stay here everyday, never run away.
#這條怎麼那麼壯啊 這條
Why is this one so bulky, this dog.
#這條是公的
This is a male?
#母的
Female
#哇 這個
Wa! Does she
#像不像走虎
look like a tiger?
#像不像老虎的那個
Does it look like a tiger, the, well...
#你看 它的皮都可以揪得到的
Look! I can hold her by the skin.
#你看 這狗 好聽話的哦
Look! This dog, is such a good dog
#快來 笑一下
Come on! Cheers!
#給攝影小哥笑一下
Give a smile to Mr Cameraman.
#他要拍你的照
He wants to give you a good shot.
#笑得多開心啊 你看
She's is smiling merrily. Look!
#它的舌頭 黑的
His tongue is black.
#哇
Wa!
#哈 就在這睡覺哈
Ha! You're taking a nap here?
#弄痛它啦 它就這樣
When I hurt her, she's always,
#用鄙視的眼神看著我 它又不敢吭聲
looking at me with a pair of disgraceful eyes. But she never dares to say anything.
#嗯 給你按按摩啊
Um! Give you a massage.
#它的腳怎麼一直趐起來
Why is her leg always getting up?
#嗯 這是甚麼
Um? What is it.
#我還以為是個跳蚤呢 不是 一坨泥
I though it were a flea. No, just dirty.
#它的鬍子
Her whiskers.
#它的鬍子好短啊
Her whiskers are very short.
#它牙齒好利呀
And her teeth are very sharp.
#額 笑一笑
Eh! Smile!
#好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
#我要去煮飯啦
I need to cook.